let me share with you a trick uh that
will allow you to keep subchart y values
files with your main chart values. yam
file and you're like well why would I do
this um as you can see here Helm Helm
template Harbor so Harbor has at least a
bitnami chart has
three um different charts involved and
the only place to look for these I've
talked about this in other videos is in
charts. loock um you can't look it up
with Helm show chart and you can't look
it up with you know get values uh or any
of those things after you even put it in
a mini Cube we tried all that so why
would you do this um the the main reason
to do this is is very simple you want
all of your values. yamel files together
because you've made customizations to
them you you've done whatever you want
to do to them and you want to store that
at that level so you can go back and do
change management and you know all of
the good things that that you do so here
is the secret and um I'm going to give
Chad GPT a little bit of credit here um
I asked chat GPT how to do it and
initially it told me that had to do with
python and then I said what about the Go
version and it kind of turned me onto
this idea and then I addited about
comment so what what this magic right
here is this is this is really if you
don't see anything else in the video
this is what this magic of yq is I love
yq if you if you haven't learned yq the
goang version micis yq you need to learn
it you need to put that tool in your
shed um and what this does is it takes
all of the values inside of this yaml
file which I'll show you in a second and
it puts them under this new root na node
key you know map key so they're all
under postgress and then it removes all
the comments and that's just that's just
to make it easier to see okay um and the
same thing here so um why am I doing
this in this build script I'm doing this
in the build script
because um you know I could have done
that right I could have altered the the
values D postgress file to be all
indented but then I would have been
messing with the original file and how
did I get those files well as is updated
is documented my updating section I I I
actually went into the night trying to
make a a Helm update I want to do Helm
show chart or Helm show lock so you can
get the actual versions which you can't
do with show chart also wanted to act
dash dash you know Helm show values--
include sub values but then it would
have to Coal the values it was really
complicated and the takeaway is I was
like screw it I'm not messing with Helm
uh I'm just going to make my build
script do the right thing and I'm going
to document in my KES app read me how I
got those values Val so the by hand
process to get those values is to do um
a show values on each of these specific
charts at a specific version and you're
probably asking how do I get that
information the only way to get that
information is to open the charts. loock
file in the chart that you have that
means you have to download the source or
get open the tar ball or whatever or go
look at the charts lock file that's the
only place it's saved unfortun the helm
command does not have show lock or
whatever and I was considering adding a
PR for that if somebody wants to help me
convince me to do that fine I didn't
care enough because I got past what I
needed and so by doing this you can see
this is actually really simplify the
creation of these values files so I've
kept the nameing convention of values.
yaml uh for the main one right that is a
pretty common convention and that's a
pre-existing convention from our k app
uh standard that we kind of follow um
and then uh in order to avoid you know
omitting or missing data that is in the
other values stuff that was implied but
never seen including the postgress
backup which is in there it just has to
be enabled which we recoded because we
didn't know it was there um these these
values files are now being saved so
let's let's look at those briefly um so
in the resources file you see values
postgress and this is the reason that I
put put that fancy yq command in there
right because this is the exactly the
same val. yl file you would expect to
find if you were Kate's appliying
postgress right because it but but
because it's not postgress because it's
a subart it is postest but it's you know
it's part of the harbor project in this
case then I'm bringing it in I'm
bringing the exact one in that the same
exact one and I validated this by doing
get keys after installing the whole
thing so I know it works but here you
got all these beautiful comments right
and this is where you would find in this
case you would find the PG dump this is
where we IP bound the PG dump command
existed already there's already a
full-blown backup in here but you just
had to enable it in fact if you go to
backup um let me go find it uh so here's
the backup and you can actually enable
it said enable to true it's false by
default right so now I just go in here
and I change this and next time that I
wanted to update the version I can just
get the um this values file against the
Upstream version without any
modification to the values file itself
uh the modification that happens to it
happens dynamically when we run build
and that's when it drops uh the comments
and and and kind of tucks all of that
file under the postgress and Rus does
the same thing so that when it's
combined and this by the way the order
matters the Valu you can use DF here if
you want instead um so when this order
comes in these things are kind of
layered over the top of each other and
uh and this this this value file at the
end which also includes postrest stuff
uh is is still kept it's still kept
right we we tested this by uh activating
uh the backup in this one and then
disabling it again in the overwriting
values of yop file and the disabling one
which means uh to use a big fancy word
that the values data uh from all three
of these is l so that ultimately you get
what you would see when you do get
values after the whole thing has been
applied and if you want to do that you
can actually build this out and do keep
CTL apply or whatever install and you
will see uh the exact same result um
you'll see the there will be a postgress
top level node and a red is post top
level node and it'll have all the data
from the original uh postc cross values
file and the redest values file and they
will all have been combined coales if
you will together and I considered you
know running a little bit of mini Cube
and doing it all and then grabbing that
combined data and putting it in but then
if you did that you would lose all that
really
useful uh uh build information uh that
you know goes into the Val I mean the
point of putting pulling the values file
out and this has become a very solid
convention in this world is is that all
of the documentation about how you would
configure your CU kubernetes application
is in the values file this is in fact so
much so that they've got parameters and
they've got you know ways to document uh
you know the the Json schema and
everything in here so you really don't
want to mess with this and and being
able to inspect this file uh at any
moment uh if you're coming to the
project new or something and you want to
know what's going on you want to read
where do I change the thing what do I
what do I do to change the image tag or
whatever this is where you would come to
do it right uh speaking of image tags uh
the IM here's an interesting case so the
actual image tag here
uh for bitnami postr is
16.4 now something that's very
interesting that I want to show you is
even though the image tag in the you
know this chart I want to show you how
that the the the last one wins because
this is this is correct right and this
is why this Arbor chart is so messed up
because this Harbor chart has a
dependency on this specific chart that
is pointed to for the image Tech 16.4
and then the bug is and this is very
much a bug um the the bug is is that the
values. yl file uh that is in Harbor
here uh oopsie where am I am I in the F
what am I doing
resources all right so uh and here
you'll see that the bit that this is
this is I've already talked about this
bug in another chart so there's this
like really outdated uh comment here it
has no relevance we're we're we're on
2.11 I'm almost done I'm making a video
and and then um and then we've got right
here we've got image do IO benom post
13.6 right so so this image tag
overrides the one in the actual chart
which is listed as a dependency and
charts. lock which is totally ass
backwards and broken and you you need to
fix it yourself if you're going to do
that that's why I found it here but let
me just prove to you that that the last
one wins and the way we'll do that is
just with a simple yq command against uh
the the postest um we'll do postgress
Post agress
SQL do image. tag in the uh resources um
I'm sorry the Manifest which is the one
that was generated with the build
command uh man where am I why are you
not why you no work
manifest
SLB
app. and oops that's why I'm using
practics
Rob oh my
God what oh right right um that's not
right um all right right right I I'm I'm
I I did the same thing I did before um
we actually need to see if the crown job
got added okay so because because this
is much more Robos right so so there it
is there's the PG dump thing and and the
way you know that this was installed is
because because it's got PG dump all in
here right then that I've already
established that that's the way to know
that that that that uh that that got but
but that's not we were looking at we
were looking for the image so let's go
um let's go look for what images uh
let's actually just GP images out of
there I'm mixing my things up uh GP
image um out of here actually image grap
uh
postgress and you'll see that this is at
postgress image 13 Even though as you
saw in the other chart it was right so
that there are a number there's there's
two fixes for this um and one of them
would be to remove to alter the the
value file the incorrect value file and
to fix it and that would mean taking
this just getting rid of it so if I get
rid of this section now it should
resolve correctly because the Upstream
chart is correct right now there's a
bunch of other stuff here that you can't
mess with so you don't don't take get
rid of that but I'm going to go ahead
and remove this because it's absolute
bull crap all right so we're gonna we're
going to take this out
um and that one I guess we could leave
postrest image
registry uh I don't know if we even want
to keep these post shag ts are
recommended um please post okay I think
all of this stuff could could get taken
out so we're going to take this
out um and just leave that there this is
stuff that was that I think is still
needed we haven't tested that yet but so
now when we run uh we run our build uh
it should actually put the right version
in and I don't know we're going to we're
going to say oh by the way I I am still
dumping the temp file this is this is
what the data looks like that is getting
uh you see with that that fancy yq magic
you see what it does it got rid of the
comments and this is the same yaml file
this is the same postr yaml file it just
put everything under postc cross SQL so
that it could be combined uh and and
override the the you know the stuff in
the other one at the right place so so
now we're going to GP for the image tag
and hopefully we'll have the right one
now we do now we have the 16.4 image tag
which is authoritative because according
to charts. loock that is the the chart
on which the harbor chart depends and
that is the the the the version and the
the ancient bug you know inclusion and
the you know the postc cross override
that was there now needs to be removed
that bug needs to be submitted to the
harbor chart I might end up doing it
myself um because 16.4 is totally valid
and it will totally work it even said
some of the documentation postrest 12
and up uh is required actually for the
latest version of Harbor the harbor uh
version
2.11 and there you go so that that's a
summary of how to how to make those
changes I actually think that that is
the most elegant way to fix this problem
uh before I did this before I included
these other charts into in the resources
file uh my fix was to uh override that
and to change that line from the other
one but now if somebody were do a get
dip against the Upstream chart values
file they would see that that entire
section has been taken out and then they
could look at the build file and go well
what are we actually using for that and
then the answer now is we are using the
postgress Upstream chart officially
we're not screwing with it and we fix
things the way you know the helm Gods
intended
I don't know what to say there it's
probably time for me to stop talking bye